<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tiernans Comms Closet</title>
    <description>Dont Ask</description>
    <link>http://blog.lotas-smartman.net/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://blog.lotas-smartman.net/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 08 May 2017 14:58:04 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 May 2017 14:58:04 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.3.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Cloudflare and the Future</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;So, you may have noticed that the site has been up and down a bit for the last day or so… And now its over SSL. Well, thats because now this site is hosted 
behind &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cloudflare.com&quot;&gt;CloudFlare&lt;/a&gt; with SSL and &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/SPDY&quot;&gt;SPDY&lt;/a&gt; enabled. But thats just one part of this post…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking at the sites i run, i have decided to make some changes. The sites running are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://tiernanotoole.ie&quot;&gt;tiernanotoole.ie&lt;/a&gt; which is a technical blog and my main email account&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.lotas-smartman.net&quot;&gt;blog.lotas-smartman.net&lt;/a&gt; which is this site, the oldest site i have. Email is still on here, but its more a legacy site…&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.geekphotographer.com&quot;&gt;geekphotographer.com&lt;/a&gt; is a photography released blog with a technical side&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://tiernanotoole.net&quot;&gt;tiernanotoole.net&lt;/a&gt; which will be a more network related site (not live yet)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://tiernanotoolephotography.com&quot;&gt;tiernanotoolephotography.com&lt;/a&gt; which will host my photograpy stuff, more business than technical…&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://miniblog.tiernanotoole.ie&quot;&gt;miniblog.tiernanotoole.net&lt;/a&gt;, a &lt;a href=&quot;http://tumblr.com&quot;&gt;Tumblr&lt;/a&gt; site for quick content, more “personal” than tech and mostly photos…&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;there are a few more (well, 30 or so domains!) but it would take too long to explain, and i cant even remember what half of them are or where…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, this site, going forward, will be more “Long Form” posts, much like the &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.lotas-smartman.net/5-screens-and-a-cloud/&quot;&gt;5+ Screens and a Cloud&lt;/a&gt; post from 2011. future posts like the &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.lotas-smartman.net/using-dropbox-as-a-personal-git-and-mercurial-storage-area/&quot;&gt;Using Dropbox 
as a personal Git and Mercurial Storage area&lt;/a&gt; post will probably go to &lt;a href=&quot;http://tiernanotoole.ie&quot;&gt;tiernanotoole.ie&lt;/a&gt; and then shorter quick posts will live on the 
&lt;a href=&quot;http://miniblog.tiernanotoole.ie&quot;&gt;miniblog.tiernanotoole.ie&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;all the blogs have RSS feeds to subscribe to, so if you want to subscribe, go forth and do so… Thanks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;–Tiernan&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.lotas-smartman.net/cloudflare-and-the-future/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.lotas-smartman.net/cloudflare-and-the-future/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Uncategorized</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Blog move details</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;yesterday i &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.lotas-smartman.net/finally-moved-to-jekyll/&quot;&gt;wrote that i had moved&lt;/a&gt; my site to &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; and i also mentioned i would post how how i was doing this. Well, this is that post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, getting data out of &lt;a href=&quot;http://wordpress.org&quot;&gt;Wordpress&lt;/a&gt; was a bit of a pain (in my case… screwing around with &lt;a href=&quot;http;//nginx.org&quot;&gt;NGinX&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.php.net&quot;&gt;PHP-FPM&lt;/a&gt;, but that is out of scope for this blog post… if you have a “normal” enough blog check out &lt;a href=&quot;https://wordpress.org/plugins/jekyll-exporter/&quot;&gt;Jekyll Exporter&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.geekphotographer.com&quot;&gt;geekphotogrpaher&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://podcast.tiernanotoole.ie&quot;&gt;Tiernans Podcast&lt;/a&gt; both wored first time…)… If not, your on your own…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, i got a zip file out of Jekyll Exporter that included all my posts (some had to be modified…) and all my images. Styles etc, not so much… But new blog, new style! (if your on an RSS reader, check out the new site &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.lotas-smartman.net&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, then i installed Jekyll on my machine… Again, out of scope for this post, but the &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; website had details on installing and running it. I installed &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sabayon.org&quot;&gt;Sabayon Linux&lt;/a&gt; on my &lt;a href=&quot;http://tiernanotoole.ie/Computers/GodBoxV2.html&quot;&gt;Godbox 2&lt;/a&gt; a while back… more on that eventually…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;so, once Jekyll was installed, i created a new site by typing&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;jekyll new blogname
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;this created a load of files under the blogname folder. I then did some tweaking… i copied all my original posts, images and pages to that folder and then ran&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;jekyll serve
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;this generates all the HTML (puts it into the _site folder in your blog directory) and then serves the html at &lt;a href=&quot;http://127.0.0.1:4000&quot;&gt;http://127.0.0.1:4000&lt;/a&gt;. Hitting that page in your favourite browser then shows you how it will look.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did some tweaks to &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com/docs/plugins/&quot;&gt;plugins&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ubuntu.com&quot;&gt;Permalinks&lt;/a&gt; to get the site the way i wanted it, but once completed, i just ran&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;jekyll build
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;all my final files where then in the _site folder. I then use &lt;a href=&quot;https://rsync.samba.org/&quot;&gt;RSync&lt;/a&gt; to transfer the contents of my _site folder to the server and heay presto! its live! Well, semi live…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main server is hosted in house, on an &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ubuntu.com&quot;&gt;Ubuntu&lt;/a&gt; box running &lt;a href=&quot;http;//nginx.org&quot;&gt;NGinX&lt;/a&gt;. But i have 3 internet connections, so i have an &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ovh.ie&quot;&gt;OVH&lt;/a&gt; box in France running both &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.varnish-cache.org/&quot;&gt;Varnish&lt;/a&gt; as a front end and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.haproxy.org/&quot;&gt;HAProxy&lt;/a&gt; as a backend. HAProxy is pointing at the 3 WAN ips i have, and if one falls over, it take it out of the loop. Varnish then is pointing at that and doing caching… Finally, to make things even more complicated (but hopefully faster) I use &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rackspace.com&quot;&gt;Rackspace Cloud&lt;/a&gt;, which in turn uses &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.akamai.com&quot;&gt;Akamai&lt;/a&gt; as a CDN for the site…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, there you have it. It is a lot more complicated then it needs to be. I could easily just generate the site and push to &lt;a href=&quot;http://aws.amazon.com/s3&quot;&gt;Amazon S3&lt;/a&gt; and do &lt;a href=&quot;http://tiernanotoole.ie/2014/01/23/CDNHostedBlog.html&quot;&gt;what i am doing on tiernanotoole.ie&lt;/a&gt; or even easier, use &lt;a href=&quot;https://pages.github.com/&quot;&gt;Github Pages&lt;/a&gt;. Hell, I use &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.github.com&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt; to host the site (privately) already, and if i use them to host it, they would build the bloody thing too! Anyway, its working, im happy, and hopefully it means i will post more often… then again, not sure… One other thing i need to do, or at least think about doing, is to &lt;a href=&quot;http://tiernanotoole.ie/2012/08/29/NewSite.html&quot;&gt;automate it&lt;/a&gt;… One of these days…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Either way, checkout the &lt;a href=&quot;http://tiernanotoole.ie/&quot;&gt;tiernanotoole.ie&lt;/a&gt; site, since there is a lot more technical stuff there, or &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.geekphotographer.com&quot;&gt;geekphotographer&lt;/a&gt; which is, obviously, for geeks and photographers!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are looking at starting a blog using Jelyll, Check out the following links:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll main site&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.jekyllbootstrap.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll Bootstrap&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com/docs/resources/&quot;&gt;Jekyll Resources&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com/docs/templates/&quot;&gt;Jekyll Template Guide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com/docs/home/&quot;&gt;Jekyll Getting started guide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;UPDATE 2015/08/13: This site is now hosted on a box in the house, but fronted by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cloudflare.com&quot;&gt;CloudFlare&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.lotas-smartman.net/blog-move-details/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.lotas-smartman.net/blog-move-details/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Uncategorized</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Finally moved to Jekyll</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Well, yesterday, after a very long abense, i &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.lotas-smartman.net/not-dead-just-lazy/&quot;&gt;said i was planning to move this site to 
Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; and after many years of thinking about it, it has finally happened. If your 
reading this, its been done… I will post more about &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;, how i moved, etc, 
soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for now, the site should still have all the same stuff the old one did, and shout 
be a LOT faster, given there is no HTML generation done when you hit the page. Also, 
with the help of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rackspace.com&quot;&gt;Rackspace&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.akamai.com&quot;&gt;Akamai&lt;/a&gt; this site should fly since its hosted 
beind their CDN product. Next is to move the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.geekphotographer.com&quot;&gt;photography blog&lt;/a&gt; and the 
&lt;a href=&quot;http://podcast.tiernanotoole.ie&quot;&gt;podcast&lt;/a&gt;, though the podcast will probably be retired sooner 
rather than later…&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 23 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.lotas-smartman.net/finally-moved-to-jekyll/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.lotas-smartman.net/finally-moved-to-jekyll/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Uncategorized</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Not dead, just lazy</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;400&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//blog.lotas-smartman.net/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/IMG_0252.jpg&quot; title=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;size-medium&quot; /&gt;
well, it’s been a while. Nearly three years. Been busy and lazy for the last while. Have started blogging at &lt;a href=&quot;http://tiernanotoole.ie&quot;&gt;Tiernanotoole.ie&lt;/a&gt; using &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;, and been trying to figure out what to do with this site. The &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.geekphotographer.com&quot;&gt;Geek photographer&lt;/a&gt; blog is still there, and between this and that, most of the updates are to the WordPress install itself. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been thinking of moving this site to Jekyll. Would just then be html being served, no database, no security updates, but i would loose the ease of posting, like now though my iPhone. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, let’s see what happens. Might get pissed off upgrading WordPress and managing the servers and move sooner rather than later. What could possibly go wrong? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[update] this is what happens when you don’t post a lot. My caching has gone nuts and that image, which was put up as an after though, won’t resize… Feck it anyway!&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.lotas-smartman.net/not-dead-just-lazy/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.lotas-smartman.net/not-dead-just-lazy/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Uncategorized</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>BITS transfer over Remote Desktop with Powershell</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;So, I have a dedicated server and the machine acts as a Hyper-V host. Only Remote Desktop is enabled on the box, for security, but the VMs have their own ports open (HTTP, SSH, etc). Transferring files between the Dedicated Server and my home network is a bit of a pain… one way is to open a port locally (SSH or FTP) and download the file from home to the dedicated box… bit of a pain, but it does work… But now i have found some magic in BITS Transfer!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bits Transfer allows you to download and upload files in the back ground, intelligently… Hence the full name of Background Intelligent Transfer Service… So, how to you get this to work with Remote Desktop?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the Remote Desktop Client, under the Local Resources Tab, under Devices and Resources, click the “More” option and select the drives you want to share out to your server. Remember, the server has access to these files… I am not sure if everyone on the server can see them, so be careful. Connect to your server and go into Computer… you should, by default, see your extra drives… they dont have real drive names though… So, what you need to do is go to the address \tsclient (should be always the same…) and you will see the drives you have shared. find the drive your interested in, find the exact file you want to copy over an Shift+Right click on the file. You will see an option to Copy As Path. Click this. Next, Open PowerShell (Should be installed on all servers, if not &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bing.com&quot;&gt;Google for it with Bing&lt;/a&gt; and find out how to install it. Once powershell is either opened or installed and opened, type “Import-Module bitstransfer”. now for the magic commands:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Start-BitsTransfer -source $sourceFile -destination $localtionFile&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
That is it… set $sourceFile to the URL of the file you want to download, and $locationFile to the place you want it placed. Powershell will show an progress bar of how the transfer is doing… But, what happens if the connection drops before the download finishes? Simple. Open your connection again, you should see your original powershell window. In here type:&lt;br /&gt;
Get-BitsTransfer | Resume-BitsTransfer&lt;br /&gt;
Now, this is looking for ALL bits transfers on the system, and then resuming them… You may want to check and see what Get-BitsTransfer shows as a result… In my case, i only want to start the jobs which are marked as having an error “TransientError” so my PowerShell Command is:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Get-BitsTransfer | Where-Object {$_.JobState -eq “TransientError” } | Resume-BitsTransfer&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
You could also use the Job ID if you have one (in my screen, its being truncated…)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, What about downloading FROM the server to your local machine? Well, in the Start-BitsTransfer, swap the source and destination… Source is a local file on your server and destination is the fileshare on TSClient you want to upload to… and the resume upload and download will work to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another interesting option is to add the -Asynchronous option to the Start-BitsTransfer command. This will run the command fully in the background. there is aslo the option of using the -Suspend, which only adds the job, but does not start it immediately. In this case you can see some info about the download using the Get-BitsTransfer command. Finally, you need to run one final command: Complete-BitsTransfer. So, You would call&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Get-BitsTransfer | Where-Object {$_.JobState -eq “Transferred” } | Complete-BitsTransfer&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
As the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.comparethemeerkat.com/&quot;&gt;MeerKat says, Simples! &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[UPDATED]&lt;/strong&gt; Want to monitor the progress of the download? &lt;strong&gt;bitsadmin /monitor&lt;/strong&gt; will show you the status of your transfer! Handy!&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 25 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.lotas-smartman.net/bits-transfer-over-remote-desktop-with-powershell/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.lotas-smartman.net/bits-transfer-over-remote-desktop-with-powershell/</guid>
        
        
        <category>HowTo</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Infinite Monkey Twitter</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Infinite_monkey_theorem&quot;&gt;Infinite Monkey Theorem&lt;/a&gt; states:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;a monkey hitting keys at random on a typewriter keyboard for an infinite amount of time will almost surely type a given text, such as the complete works of William Shakespeare.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This made me think… and more importantly, think about Twitter… I am thinking about my Final Year college project, and have been playing with the Twitter Streams API for the last few days. So far, i have about 650k of tweets to play with, but it made me think about using “fake” data for tweets… take the following as an example:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;monkey tosses coin to say if its a response or a new tweet. if its a response, a new coin is used to figure if he responds to some he follows or someone he does not follow… if he does not follow, finally tosses a third time to figure if he wants to respond to a “famous” (more than 10000 followers) or not other monkey…&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;if response, find a tweet to respond to&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;monkey randomly takes a number from 1 to (140 – 1 (@) + twitter user name + 1 (space)). this is char count&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;monkey now tosses a coin to figure if he wants to add a hash tag… if yes, he tosses again to either use a random trending hashtag or a completely different one…&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;finally, the monkey, using the number of characters left, randomly hits the keyboard and makes a nonsense tweet…&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;this is much how i tweet at &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/tiernano&quot;&gt;@tiernano&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;http://blog.lotas-smartman.net/wp-includes/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif&quot; alt=&quot;:)&quot; class=&quot;wp-smiley&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;anyway, using this as an idea, and adding in monkeys following each other depending on how they feel (more coin tossing) you could get a lot of tweets using some lower powered machines (worker nodes) and some beefy hardware… this is starting to sound like an interesting problem… now to figure out more… leave it with me…&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.lotas-smartman.net/infinite-monkey-twitter/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.lotas-smartman.net/infinite-monkey-twitter/</guid>
        
        <category>Code</category>
        
        <category>monkey</category>
        
        <category>Twitter</category>
        
        
        <category>Code</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Tiernan&amp;#8217;s Podcast, Episode 1</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;So, my new podcast is now live! I am a podcaster again! for the next 3 weeks (Today, Tuesday 20th and Tuesday 27th) a new episode will auto publish. If you want to get them on your iPod, iPhone, i(Insert name here), Windows Phone, etc… Subscribe to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/TiernansPodcast&quot;&gt;PodCast Feed here&lt;/a&gt;. Or you can download the files directly from &lt;a href=&quot;http://podcast.tiernanotoole.ie/index.php/archives/8&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 13 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.lotas-smartman.net/tiernans-podcast-episode-1/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.lotas-smartman.net/tiernans-podcast-episode-1/</guid>
        
        <category>Podcast</category>
        
        
        <category>Articles</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>5+ Screens and a cloud</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.lotas-smartman.net/wp-content/uploads/2011/11/image002.gif&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignright&quot; title=&quot;image002&quot; src=&quot;http://blog.lotas-smartman.net/wp-content/uploads/2011/11/image002.gif&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;371&quot; height=&quot;242&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Microsoft have talked about their idea of “Three screens and a cloud” for the future of computing. The idea is you have your PC (Laptop or Desktop, or Tablet once Windows 8 ships), your Smart Phone and your TV with an Xbox connected. And all your data is shared between them with the cloud… but it has made me think… Why only 3 screens? Why not 5?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why 5+&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 5+ screens I am thinking about are as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The usual 3 suspects: Main PC, Smart Phone and TV…&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Your Watch&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A Tablet (secondary machine)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Possibly your car in-dash screen (could be your smartphone or use your smartphone for processing and internet connection)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.lotas-smartman.net/wp-content/uploads/2011/11/image004.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-4248 alignleft&quot; title=&quot;image004&quot; src=&quot;http://blog.lotas-smartman.net/wp-content/uploads/2011/11/image004.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;93&quot; height=&quot;119&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;The idea of using your watch as a screen is something that is not exactly new. The original Microsoft based Spot watch used an FM signal to get data from the MSN direct service. This included weather, and if I remember correctly, also included calendar items.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In recent times, companies like Sony Ericson have developed their LiveView: a screen which connects to your Android phone using Bluetooth and shows information like phone status, weather, Facebook friends, and more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;iPod Nano&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.lotas-smartman.net/wp-content/uploads/2011/11/nanowatch.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignleft size-full wp-image-4252&quot; title=&quot;nanowatch&quot; src=&quot;http://blog.lotas-smartman.net/wp-content/uploads/2011/11/nanowatch.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;334&quot; height=&quot;295&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;If you look at the new &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.apple.com/ipodnano/&quot;&gt;iPod Nano&lt;/a&gt;, we are getting close… there are even watch straps for the Nano. Apple’s latest Nano came with extra watch faces since people wanted it! But the Nano is missing a couple of thing:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Really needs Bluetooth! Not only for listening to music with, but also for talking to different devices… imaging if your Nano talked to your iPhone and got data streams like news, weather, phone call, email and SMS information, your next calendar appointment?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Apps! It seems as if the Nano is running a micro copy of iOS, so in theory, it should be able to run iOS apps… slightly modified apps mind you. And I can’t see it having enough power to run Angry Birds, but basic info apps should be enough…&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Vibrate function: the ability to “buzz” when something happens… I carry my phone in an inside pocket or a pocket with other things, so I don’t usually feel it buzzing or hear it ringing… but if my “watch” did, I would notice!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A proper docking station: I would like, before I go to bed, to stick my “watch” in a docking station, which both charges and syncs contents to the device. It would also sync with the dock, telling it what time I want to be woken up the next morning.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Your Car&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://miniblog.tiernanotoole.ie/my-new-car&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-medium wp-image-4251 alignright&quot; title=&quot;p93.jpg.scaled1000&quot; src=&quot;http://blog.lotas-smartman.net/wp-content/uploads/2011/11/p93.jpg.scaled1000-300x224.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; height=&quot;224&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;My car is currently a 2006 BMW 520D. It has the professional navigation system, which includes an 8.5” widescreen display in dash board. This is used by most of the functions in the car: audio, navigation, communications, in car information and climate control, all controlled by the iDrive. If your car could connect to your phone (mine already does for Bluetooth phone calls) to get information, data and more, it could be much more interesting:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Any music on your phone available at your fingertips.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Be able to call up data from the internet, giving you tips on traffic, your latest calendar appointments, friends’ check-ins, and more.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Your car being able to send data to your mechanic over the internet for diagnostics information. It could also send data like millage, fuel usage, etc., so you can see how your fuel economy is doing…&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Apps, working both on your phone and your car, for operations like Navigation and Music.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BMW already have this with its &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bmw.com/com/en/newvehicles/1series/activee/2011/showroom/edrive/connecteddrive.html&quot;&gt;ConnectedDrive&lt;/a&gt; which does a lot of these functions, but currently only works with the iPhone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Your secondary machine&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most people have one main PC. Be it a big honking workstation, like the GodBox, or a standard Laptop or Desktop machine, it usually is something fairly powerful, which could be used for anything from Internet browsing and email, to syncing your music and videos to your devices (iDevices, Windows Phones, etc) to video editing and photo processing, to developing code. Either way, it’s a large enough machine with enough power to do what is required.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But, what about the second machine? The machine you would use for tasks requiring less power… this is where I think the likes of an iPad, Windows 8 Tablet or Android Tablet come in. these are thin clients, but still have a bit of power to do work on them directly. You’re not going to open your iPad and do coding directly on it (well, maybe you could…) but you may login to a remote machine and tweak code, or check how a build is doing. The “secondary” machine is perfect for this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Think of it as a medium build machine. I mentioned the idea of a Medium Build Client when &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.lotas-smartman.net/more-on-desktop-in-the-cloud&quot;&gt;talking about Cloud Desktops&lt;/a&gt; a while back. My thought of it was around the Windows 8 Tablet. Since the Windows 8 Tablet can be a proper Intel processor, like the Build Tablet that was handed out at the Build conference, can actually run as a full Windows PC, and runs Visual Studio “11”, I see it as something that can be used as mostly a full machine, but also as a thin client for connection to larger machines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So, what is the ideal Solution?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t think we are there yet, so there is no solution at the moment, but what would ideal would be the following walk though:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Be woken up in the morning by my Alarm clock, which is acting as a dock for both my Phone and Smart Watch. The watch’s time would be kept in sync with all other devices. So, you stick the watch on, grab your phone and tablet (which is also syncing with your main workstation) and head down for breakfast.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Reading the news and checking mail on your tablet, your watch buzzes to remind you about a meeting in about an hour and a half. It knows it’s going to take you about 50min to drive to work, but traffic is a bit heavy, so it warns you to leave a little earlier. You finish up and jump in the car. Your phone and car talk to each other. Since your car knows your heading to work, it finds the route you usually take, and checks traffic information. It notices there are delays on your usual route, and decides to re-route you so you get in to your meeting on time.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You get to the car park, leave your car and head to the office, a 5 min walk. While walking down the road, you’re listening to music on your Bluetooth headphones from your phone, and your watch buzzes. You have a quick look and it’s a text from someone coming to the meeting asking where it is. You hit the call button on your watch and have a chat with the client, giving them directions. When you get to the office, you hit the send location option on your phone and send them an email with your current location, so they can find you on their phone.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;During the day, you use your tablet to work, connected to an external screen, with a Bluetooth keyboard and mouse. 90% of your work is done on a remote machine in your datacentre, allowing you to get extra power and machines as needed. Your servers all live in the cloud, and your data is backed up regularly. All your code is stored in your code repo (SVN, GIT, Mercurial, TFS) and if your machine goes down, you can spin up a new instance, and get back to where you left off pretty quickly.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://miniblog.tiernanotoole.ie/my-new-dailywtf-coffee-cup-thanks-to-newrelic&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignleft size-thumbnail wp-image-4255&quot; title=&quot;coffeecup&quot; src=&quot;http://blog.lotas-smartman.net/wp-content/uploads/2011/11/coffeecup1-150x150.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;150&quot; height=&quot;150&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;At about 3 o’clock, you hit the slump and head to the local Starbucks to have a coffee and get out of the office for a half hour. You head down with the tablet, your phone and your headphones. Sitting in the back of the Starbucks, drinking your coffee, using their wifi and listening to music, you start looking through email and documents. You’re on instant messenger and keeping an eye on your bug tracker when you notice an important bug for a section of code you own coming in. Since you don’t have as much bandwidth to work on the remote desktop with as high a fidelity as you do in the office, you update your local copy of the code to the latest version, open your copy of visual studio, take out your travel keyboard and mouse and start coding the fix. You run your tests, check in, and a Continuous integration build gets kicked off… at this point you finish your coffee and head back to the office. On your way, your watch buzzes to tell you the build has completed and all tests have passed. You send a “deploy to test” message from your watch’s custom application, and head to your office. You get back and all is good with the build and the world…&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You’re about to head home after a long day in the office. You decided to chance your arm at cooking a Thai Green Curry. You check your tablet to see what is in the house and what is needed for the curry. You add the list of missing ingredients to your to-do list, which is synced with your watch. You head to the car park, hop in the car and hit the start button. As you are driving out of the car park, the car notices the shopping list. It finds a local shop on the way home, but also realizes you need diesel for your car. It adds the shop and finds the cheapest fuel station on your way home, to your navigation system, and directs you to the quickest route with the least amount of traffic.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.lotas-smartman.net/wp-content/uploads/2011/11/image006.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignleft size-full wp-image-4249&quot; title=&quot;image006&quot; src=&quot;http://blog.lotas-smartman.net/wp-content/uploads/2011/11/image006.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;322&quot; height=&quot;199&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;After filling the car with fuel, and as your heading to the shop, your car informs you that your Miles per Gallon since the last fill up was about 10% off your average. It notices your last service was nearly 12 thousand miles previously and suggests a service. You confirm and the car books itself in for a service, adding the details to your calendar.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You arrive at the shop, and take out your phone. You pull up the shopping list in a custom application, which knows the layout of the given shop, and shows you where the items you are looking for will be. You pick up the items, scanning them with your phone as you go along. Your phone gives you a running total, and pops up with some offers as you scan items. “Did you know the shop’s own brand of this item is 25% cheaper?” or “you usually buy this every 2 months, and it has a shelf life of 10. If you purchase 2 of these now, you get a third one free”. When you arrive at the checkout, you tap your phone on the NFC reader. The assistant asks if everything scanned correctly, and pay using the NCF system in your phone. You place everything in a bag and head out to the car and drive home.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Once home, you place the tablet in the kitchen dock. You load up the recipe and it starts talking you though what needs to be done. You miss a step, so you ask it to repeat the last item. While you are waiting for it to finish, you load up the Netflix application and see what is in your instant queue. You start looking though new releases and see a new film you would like to watch. You add that to your queue, and finish cooking your meal.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.lotas-smartman.net/wp-content/uploads/2011/11/image008.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-full wp-image-4250 alignright&quot; title=&quot;image008&quot; src=&quot;http://blog.lotas-smartman.net/wp-content/uploads/2011/11/image008.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;221&quot; height=&quot;138&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;You head to the sitting room, lights automagically come on, and you turn on the TV and Xbox. You tell the Kinect to load up Netflix and select the film you want to watch. It dims the lights, closes the curtains and starts playing the film. You sit back with a beer and your curry, and relax.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;After a few more beers, a very tasty curry, and an enjoyable film, you head to bed. You stick the tablet in its charging station, your phone and watch in their docks, and yourself into bed… it will all start again the next morning.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This idea is not all that “pie in the sky” as it might sound. We have the Technology, we have the ability, we just need to link it all together… it’s the magic glue that is going to need to be developed, and I am now just wondering who is going do develop the magic glue? Apple? Microsoft? Google? They all could do it, Microsoft probably being the closest, but the question is not who will get there first, but who will do it the most integrated?&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.lotas-smartman.net/5-screens-and-a-cloud/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.lotas-smartman.net/5-screens-and-a-cloud/</guid>
        
        <category>Apple</category>
        
        <category>BMW</category>
        
        <category>car</category>
        
        <category>cloud</category>
        
        <category>google</category>
        
        <category>iPad</category>
        
        <category>iPod Nano</category>
        
        <category>microsoft</category>
        
        <category>Phone</category>
        
        <category>tablet</category>
        
        <category>tv</category>
        
        <category>watch</category>
        
        <category>Windows 8</category>
        
        
        <category>Articles</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>New Backup plan&amp;#8230; out with Jungle Disk and ZManda Cloud Backup, in with CrashPlan, MySQLBF and SqlBF&amp;#8230;</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;[&lt;strong&gt;UPDATE&lt;/strong&gt;: After a few days, i tried CrashPlan Pro on a 30 day trial… Now i find out that its not available outsite the US and Canada… Its a bit hiden in their FAQ… So, back in search i go!]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My current backup strategy is a long and convoluted one, but it did work… until i shut a lot of stuff down… now i am starting to re-think my plan… first the existing “plan”…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;my main laptop, a Mac Book Pro, is backed up to my Main Workstation (AKA the GodBox) via iSCSI. The &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.lotas-smartman.net/category/workstation-v-next&quot;&gt;GodBox&lt;/a&gt; is running Windows 2008 R2 Server, and has the &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.technet.com/b/virtualization/archive/2011/04/04/free-microsoft-iscsi-target.aspx&quot;&gt;free Microsoft iSCSI Target&lt;/a&gt; installed. I am sharing 2 300Gb VHDs to the MacBook Pro, and those are in RAID 1 on the laptop. Time Machine then backs up to this drive. Also, the iTunes Music, Movies, Apps and TV Shows, and also photos from my camera are also backed up to Jungle Disk. Currently this weighs in at about 160Gb…&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The GodBox itself has a couple of RAIDed Drives (I know, i know… RAID is not backup…). So, my Photos are stored on a RAID 1 array, which is then backed up using Jungle Disk. The photos college is weighing in at about 180Gb or so… probably more.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I have a dedicated server in Germany (this is where this site is being served from… Hello from Germany) and that has the actual contents of the site, database, images, etc. these are currently backed up regularly (every 3 hours for a incremental backup, nightly for a Full backup). I am using &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.zmanda.com/cloud-backup.html&quot;&gt;ZManda Cloud Backup&lt;/a&gt; for this. ZManda has the advantage of backing up SQL and MySQL server, as well as SharePoint and Exchange.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There is a machine in the house which acts as an internal Git server (Linux, SSH, Git… simple). &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.jugneldisk.com&quot;&gt;JungleDisk&lt;/a&gt; was installed on this and backed up the folder where Git lived. works grand…&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, there are a couple of outstanding issues with this setup:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;for the amount of data i am storing (About 500Gb give or take) with JungleDisk, its costing me about $80 a month. Its costing me about the same for a Dedicated Server, and it is &lt;strong&gt;about the same cost of a 1Tb drive, every month&lt;/strong&gt;!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I have logged into the Dedicated server a few times over the last while and found that ZManda was using 900Mb of RAM. Restarting the service solves the issue, but its still a bit of a pain to restart every few days. ZManda released a Version 4 of their ZCB software. I am still on 3.x since MySQL backup was not added to Version 4 yet…&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If i want to use the same software to backup files around the house, but not in the cloud, ZManda can do it, but JungleDisk cannot.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I am using 2 different backup systems…&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;JungleDisk charge $2 per client machine per month, and $4 per server per month (includes some storage with that price… check their site for the latest). Storage is then either charged at about $0.15 per month if you use their API key, or if you use your own, Amazon will charge you… They also use with Amazon S3 or RackSpace Cloud for storage.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;ZManda is a one off fee per month ($4.95) and you can use that one license to backup as many machines you want. storage is charged at $0.15 per GB, and they are offering 25Gb free… the 25Gb is based on each AWS Region giving you 5Gb free… I suppose since a &lt;a href=&quot;http://aws.amazon.com/about-aws/whats-new/2011/11/08/Announcing-new-us-west-oregon-region/&quot;&gt;new Region just opened in Oregon&lt;/a&gt;, that could now be 30Gb…&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, i went looking, and i think I found a solution… Some investigation still needed, but we are getting there… here is the plan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The MacBook Pro will still be using TimeMachine to backup to the GodBox using iSCSI, but the plan will be the GodBox gives it 500Gb of storage already RAIDed… Music, Movies, Photos and Apps will be backed up to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.crashplan.com&quot;&gt;CrashPlan&lt;/a&gt;. They plan i am looking at will cost me about $12 per month and give me the ability to backup up to 10 machines and gives me Unlimited space… We all know what Unlimited means, but it should be enough… Also, CrashPlan gives me the option to backup to my own machines. So, these files will also get backed up to the GodBox.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Photos and important files on the GodBox will also be backed up to CrashPlan. Less important files, but files i want “safe” will be backed up to my &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.drobo.com&quot;&gt;Drobo&lt;/a&gt;, which currently has about 4Tb usable. The MacBook Pro files will also be dropped in here.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Server in Germany will get backed up to CrashPlan too…. I am liking this idea already… Very simple. I am going to use 2 pieces of software to backup SQL and MySQL: &lt;a href=&quot;http://sqlbackupandftp.com/&quot;&gt;SQL Backup and FTP&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://mysqlbackupftp.com/&quot;&gt;MySQL Backup and FTP&lt;/a&gt;. Been using the free version for a while, and they do a nice job. Would need to go for the Pro Version (About $50 for MySQL edition and $60 for the MSSQL Edition) but that will backup to a location that CrashPlan will watch, and all the magic will be done then. Any files i want backed up will also end up in CrashPlan.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Since CrashPlan allows me to backup up to 10 machines in the cloud, i can add more as needed. Also, machines in the house that would not require cloud or offsite backup can be backed up to other machines in the house without any issues.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This should save me a bit of money over time… My first months outlay will be a little more than my usual JungleDisk bill…. After next month, things should start paying for themself…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ohhh, and while i am at it, the FREE CrashPlan software allows you to do 95% of what i mentioned above… Actually, more than 95%… the only things it wont do is Cloud Backup (you can still backup to your own machine offsite or a friends machine somewhere) and Backup Sets (Say you want your &lt;strong&gt;Documents in the Cloud, but your Music on internal machines, they could be different backup sets&lt;/strong&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[&lt;strong&gt;Full Disclosure&lt;/strong&gt; I am paying full price for the service and software above at the moment (on a 30 day trial for CrashPlan, and looking into the SQL and MySQL backup software currently) so this is just what i am planning on doing, not an advertisement…]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
    
    &lt;td&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
    
    &lt;td&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
    
    &lt;td&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
    
    &lt;td&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.lotas-smartman.net/new-backup-plan-out-with-jungle-disk-and-zmanda-cloud-backup-in-with-crashplan-mysqlbf-and-sqlbf/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.lotas-smartman.net/new-backup-plan-out-with-jungle-disk-and-zmanda-cloud-backup-in-with-crashplan-mysqlbf-and-sqlbf/</guid>
        
        <category>Backup</category>
        
        <category>CrashPlan</category>
        
        <category>GodBox</category>
        
        <category>iSCSI</category>
        
        <category>Jungle Disk</category>
        
        <category>Jungle Disk Server</category>
        
        <category>MySQL</category>
        
        <category>SQL</category>
        
        <category>ZCB</category>
        
        <category>Zmanda</category>
        
        
        <category>Articles</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Using Dropbox as a personal Git and Mercurial Storage area</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This is something i have been using for a while now, and though it might be an idea to write a quick post explaining how to set Dropbox up as a folder to push your Git and Mercurial files to… But first, why would you want to?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, you have a project you want to work on with multiple machines, and you want a source control system to easily manage files and state. You decided to use Git or Mercurial. I am not going to tell you which one to use… I use both for different projects. Anyway, you have decided to use Git or Mercurial, and you now want to be able to access the files from multiple locations. Since these locations are all your machines  (hopefully), you need to have a location that all machines can access. so, with the help of this tutorial, you can use Dropbox as your shared location. the following steps will need to be setup only once. When adding extra machines, follow the steps further on down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;First, you will need a Dropbox Account. If you don’t have one, &lt;a href=&quot;http://db.tt/j0Bv5y7&quot;&gt;click here and sign up&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;download the Dropbox installer, and link your machine. when installing, you will be asked to set the default location of your Dropbox folder, or a custom location. I picked the default location, and as i am running Windows 7, my Dropbox location will be at c:\users\tiernano\dropbox. yours will be different…&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;next, you will need either Git or Mercurial for Windows. &lt;a href=&quot;https://code.google.com/p/msysgit/&quot;&gt;msysgit&lt;/a&gt; is what i use for git on Windows. &lt;a href=&quot;http://mercurial.selenic.com/wiki/WindowsInstall&quot;&gt;Mercurial have a Windows installer also&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;so now, we will branch out into either Git or Mercurial tasks:&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;for GIT:&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Open Git Bash from the Start menu&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;you are now in a Unix-ish style command prompt… if you are not familiar with Unix… this might be interesting…&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;first, your Dropbox location will be at ~/Dropbox (~/ being your home directory)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;cd into your ~/Dropbox folder, and create a folder called git (this is what i did, you may want to be different)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;cd into your git folder, and create a new directory called yourproject.git (again, change it to your liking…)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;cd into the yourproject.git folder and type &lt;strong&gt;git init –bare.&lt;/strong&gt; this creates a bare repo for you to use. since this is in your Dropbox folder, all your machines synced with Dropbox will get this folder soon…&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;next, create a working folder.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;decided where you want to put this (ideally, not on your Dropbox folder)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;so, in my case i have a folder in my Documents folder in my home directory called project. I type &lt;strong&gt;cd ~/Documents/project&lt;/strong&gt; to get to this folder.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;when in this folder, type &lt;strong&gt;git init&lt;/strong&gt;. this folder is now a git working folder.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;add your files as needed. **git add &lt;filename&gt;** will add a file to git. **git commit –m “your message” –a** will commit all modified files on your repo with the message “Your Message” to the repo… Have a look for a [git Tutorial][4] to find more.&lt;/filename&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;next, add a remote to your current repo. &lt;strong&gt;git remote add dropbox ~/Dropbox/git/yourproject.git&lt;/strong&gt; will add your dropbox as a remote repo.  typing &lt;strong&gt;git push dropbox master&lt;/strong&gt; will push your master branch to Dropbox .&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;that’s most of what you need to know.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;For Mercurial, the following needs to be done&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;open a command prompt, and cd into your Dropbox folder.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;create a folder, i called mine hg (the mercurial command is HG…)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;in your hg folder, create a folder called myproject.hg.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;cd into the folder and type &lt;strong&gt;hg init.&lt;/strong&gt; this creates a Mercurial directory.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;next, go to the directory you want to use for your project.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;type **hg clone &lt;full path=&quot;&quot; to=&quot;&quot; your=&quot;&quot; myproject.hg=&quot;&quot; folder=&quot;&quot;&gt;**. if hg is setup correctly, all should be grand. hg add and hg commit files, and then hg push to the Dropbox location.&lt;/full&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;if you want to add a new machine to your git repo, find your directory you want to clone to and type &lt;strong&gt;git clone ~/Dropbox/git/yourproject.git yourproject&lt;/strong&gt;. your working directory is now in the yourproject folder. &lt;strong&gt;git push&lt;/strong&gt; will push back to Dropbox . &lt;strong&gt;git pull&lt;/strong&gt; will pull from Dropbox.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;the **hg clone &lt;full path=&quot;&quot; to=&quot;&quot; your=&quot;&quot; myproject.hg=&quot;&quot; folder=&quot;&quot;&gt; **will also work for adding extra machines to your repo.&lt;/full&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;hopefully this explains everything… any questions, leave a comment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dotnetkicks.com/kick/?url=http%3a%2f%2fblog.lotas-smartman.net%2fusing-dropbox-as-a-personal-git-and-mercurial-storage-area&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://dotnetkicks.com/Services/Images/KickItImageGenerator.ashx?url=http://blog.lotas-smartman.net/using-dropbox-as-a-personal-git-and-mercurial-storage-area/&quot; alt=&quot;kick it on DotNetKicks.com&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.lotas-smartman.net/using-dropbox-as-a-personal-git-and-mercurial-storage-area/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.lotas-smartman.net/using-dropbox-as-a-personal-git-and-mercurial-storage-area/</guid>
        
        <category>dropbox</category>
        
        <category>git</category>
        
        <category>mercurial</category>
        
        <category>Source Control</category>
        
        
        <category>HowTo</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
